We got our guy.
>> Jason, I think a lot of people would say
this is a top 10 player that that slid
down to 15. Is is this just too good to
pass up?
>> Yeah, absolutely. Um, now time will
tell. You know, we think very highly of
him. Obviously, think he's a great
player.
you know, there were very few scenarios
where we thought he'd be there, but um
there was scenarios um and we're very
excited. So, it's uh I've probably never
seen a more excited draft room.
>> What do you like best about his game?
>> Um
I love he's very unique where he's got a
un great blend of power and athleticism.
He can bend. Um he's got get off. He's
very powerful. He's got very uh
explosive uh not just athleticism but
powerful hands, powerful uh strength. Um
and he plays very edgy. Yeah, he plays
with a chip on his shoulder.
You guys do extensive work on these
prospects and obviously for us news
surfaced, you know, less than two weeks
ago about the motor vehicle accident
that he was involved in in 2024, but
you've done a lot of work on him as a
person. What What can you tell people
that maybe have concerns about him?
>> Well, we've been doing work um we'll
start the process for next year's draft
next week. So, our scouts, um, shout out
Caesar, uh, Rivera. Um, he's been on it
for a long time. We've known about this
for a long time now. I know I know it
just came out a couple weeks ago. It was
a it was a very tragic, um, accident,
um, tragic experience for for the
family. And it's it's, you know, it's
something you never want to see happen.
But um you know he's
he's a good person. Um was involved in
something that uh you know none of us
ever want to be involved in and um never
want any of our loved ones to be
involved in. So but um you know he loves
football. He loves football.
>> He was coached by Jason Taylor, Pro
Football Hall of Famer um who has called
him a professional. the way that he
approaches that uh when you when you see
his production and when he gets that
type of professional level tulage, does
that just make the decision even better
when when you hear comments like that?
Yeah, you love to be able to draft
players that come from great programs
and have been coached very well. And I
know our coaches have a very good uh
relationship, a lot of our coaches do
with with Jason and um we've been
talking we obviously talk with him and
and you know we like we do all prospects
and their coaches but to to draft a
player that's come from a program like
that that's uh you know excellent
program to say the least uh it's just
makes the process a little bit easier.
Um, and you have a little bit more faith
in, you know, the development of the
player.
>> Jason, you know, I'm sure you looked at
me, too, but like this guy's only 21
years old. To get a guy that's that
young that has that big of a ceiling,
how how encouraging is that?
>> Yeah. No, it's it's it's great. You
know, like I I think I told you guys
before, we we I mean, you you don't
necessarily factor age. Um, but you
know, it's something and uh, you know,
it's one step at a time. He he still has
to come in here. We're not anointing him
the, you know, into the Ring of Honor or
Hall of Fame yet, but uh, but, you know,
we certainly like everything about him
and we're very excited about it.
>> What do you think his addition does for
Yabi on the other side?
Well, I think you know, you add a player
like Reuben and he does what we hope he
can do and think he can do. I should say
think, not hope. You can redact that. Um
he um it opens a lot of things up. It
makes everybody along the D line better
when you can have two, you know, edge
presence presences. Um you know, the the
line the protections don't slide as
much. You have to decide where to slide
them. um opens things up. So I think
it's you know potentially now we we
David Walker you know we have you know
we have we have a arsenal there right
now that um we feel good a very good
rotation. So um with with Quan and you
know still have Nelly and all that it's
you know you can't have too many. I say
it every year but then it just doesn't
work out that we can draft one at a
premium but now we did. So, um hopefully
um hopefully we can reap the rewards
here.
>> When you're when you're looking at these
guys and then ultimately setting your
board, you're not just looking at the
player, you're looking at the person.
Your locker room that you have right now
is proof of that. What was it that
convinced you that he was a Buccaneer
man?
>> Um his passion for the game, his passion
to want to be the best. Um,
we like his his edge that he brings out
there and you know the guy practices the
same way that he plays and football is,
you know, one of the most important
things in his life.
>> When you look at the arm length is what
it is, right? It's shorter than than 31
in.
Kalasha Cany doesn't have the longest
arms. How does does Bane overcome that?
Is it is it just the the quick speed to
power? Is it the the ability to dip and
rip and and avoid the offensive tackles?
How does he overcome that for you on
tape?
>> I think one of his
um assets is his low center of gravity
and his power, his strength and his um
urgency. I mean, Mike Tyson had short
arms, too. So, um you know, he tries to
win every every rep, and he usually
does. Jason, is that doesn't always line
up so well that your most obvious
positional needs line up with the best
player. How much easier does that make a
pick when it does that?
>> Yeah, I know. It makes it very easy. So,
um, like I said before, there's a lot of
celebrating going on right now and
probably not going to trade back in the
first round. Here's a Didn't mean to let
the cat out of the bag, so I'm probably
going to go up and have a couple pops.
when you had I mean just some early on
in the draft, you know, you saw a couple
edge guys come off right away. Did you
have concern that that was going to that
trend was going to kind of continue?
>> Yeah, there's always that nervousness.
Um I had to stay calm and uh once again
resist kind of reminded me a little bit
of the year that we drafted Vita.
Resist. We had some teams calling seeing
if we wanted to come up. So, we had some
teams seeing if we wanted to go back,
but once uh he was there, I didn't want
to risk that uh scenario. And uh you
know, it's always nice to pick up picks
um which is something I love to do, but
um when he's sitting there, we just had
to turn it in. So, I waited a couple
minutes, but it uh
>> You mentioned that you were surprised.
Maybe not surprised, the right word, but
you're glad he was there, obviously. Um,
why do you have a theory as to to why he
was still there? Like do you think it
was any of the stuff that's come out? Do
you think it's his character? Like what
what would cause him to fall or just
other teams with other needs?
>> That could be a combination of the other
teams other needs. Um there's some
really good football players uh that
went in front of him and there's, you
know, we had a a quarterback that went
>> and then we had, you know, some
offensive linemen and
>> pushed him down
>> and pushed him down a little bit and
it's goes to show you that, you know, a
lot of teams have a lot of needs and you
know, your board is, you know, you try
to set it best the best available
player, but you know, it always enters
your mind when you have needs and this
one, you know, we had them we had them
very high up on the court. So, um,
probably would have took him a lot
earlier. So,
>> when did you think he might really be in
play? I mean, the Cowboys took downs,
you know, but was that maybe
>> I think it was around then. Yeah.
>> Jason, in your in your call with him
because he's he slid further down than
many thought and all the stuff that has
kind of been coming up recently. Did you
get a sense in your conversation that he
comes in with an extra added edge
motivation to him because of this maybe
night didn't play out exactly how he
thought it might go?
>> Well, keep in mind it was a pretty short
call and he was very emotional as we
were. Um and um he was just very very
grateful that uh that he was coming
here. So I think I asked him first thing
was picked up the phone. I said, "What
are you doing the next 5 to 10 years?"
He says, "I'm going to be a buck." And
he was he was very emotional. So I
wanted him to I didn't want to get into
a deep conversation with him and neither
did Todd. I wanted him to celebrate with
his family. And I know that's a big
night for him.
>> What what what does that mean for you on
a personal level when you get to make a
phone call like that? And then on top of
the fact that I'm sure he's been dealing
with a lot over the last two weeks
obviously like that's that I'm sure it's
been an emotional roller coaster for him
>> to make that call in a way that says,
"Hey, we see you like and we want you
here."
>> Yeah. Well, it's Yeah. I' I've never
received that call. So, I can't tell you
how he uh how he uh how he feels, but I
can only imagine. It's It's got to be uh
you know, it's been a long process for
these guys. a lot of visits, a lot of
training, combine, all that stuff. For
it to to come to an end for I mean this
that process come to an end, it's got to
be a relief. But then also just I think
he was genuinely very excited to
be a Buck. So I know a lot of former
Bucks have already reached out to me. So
it's it's it's a
>> What was Todd's reaction or statements
in there? He was just very excited. You
know, he's a hell of a football player
and he's uh the type of player that
we've been kind of focused on here um to
bring in and um so he was he was very
excited. Todd keeps it pretty close to
the vest. He was pretty excited though.
>> You said former Bucks contact you uh was
sat one of them.
>> Well, my phone is buzzing right now as
we're talking so I'm sure he'll be one
of them soon. Um,
so it's uh it's a lot. It's a lot.
>> Anything else?
>> Jason, last year you mentioned uh Mechco
Ibuka was a top 10 talent when you took
him at number 19. Just how high did the
organization feel on Ruben?
>> Like in the same ballpark?
>> Felt very high.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. We still have a contract to do.
All right. So,
>> all right. Thanks, guys. It's done.